BLAIR DOWLING

Blair.A.R.Dowling@gmail.com | (561) 846-1376 | Boynton Beach, FL 33426

Summary

Driven & detailed oriented supervisor with five+ years of experience in management. Passionate about developing businesses & optimizing their efficiency. At St. Andrew's Country Club increased delivery of goods efficiency by 44%. Looking to use managerial & organizational skills to not only improve organizational processes & efficiency but also be a part of an award winning team.

Skills -

- Adaptability
- Leadership
- Problem Solving
- Critical Thinking
- Business Analysis

- Administration
- Project Management
- Optimization
- Customer Service
- Willingness To Learn

Experience

St. Andrew's Country Club Boca Raton, FL **Supervisor** 12/2016 - 11/2021

- Developed, supervised & managed the Food and Beverage Take-Out operation
- Created & implemented employee training manuals to ensure quality service
- Managed the daily operation of five to ten people
- Improved delivery service by problem solving with creative & effective solutions to increase efficiency by 44%
- Mitigated issues by acting as liaison between customers & staff, and also between departments
- Designed & implemented marketing material
- Collaborated with the Director of Purchasing to monitor & manage inventory control

Duffy's Sports Grill Boynton Beach, FL **Server Shift Leader** 02/2011 - 12/2020

- Ensured the restaurant was up to standards by ensuring servers completed their closing responsibilities.
- Trained and acclimated new servers to restaurant's culture & operations through communication and leadership
- Created positive guest experience by listening to guest needs and recommending options to meet requests using persuasive speaking skills
- Provided exceptional service to high volume of daily customers by implementing teamwork & communication skills
- Assisted management with liquor inventory, including weekly counting, imputing invoices, and ordering

L. B. Cleaners West Palm Beach, FL Owner/ Operator & CFO 05/2019 - 06/2020

- Developed, started, operated, managed operations & closed a partnership business that had a positive net income each year
- Set pricing structures according to market analytics and emerging trends.
- Analyzed client business needs and assisted in determining appropriate resources and strategies
- Oversaw project execution, phase progress, workmanship and team performance to drive on-time completion of services

 Assisted staff with resolving complex customer issues and implementing targeted solutions

Bed Bath & Beyond Delray Beach, FL

Customer Service & Sales Associate 08/2010 - 10/2013

- Established positive rapport with customers, managers & customer service team members to maintain a positive & successful work environment.
- Maintained knowledge of company products and services to promptly resolve complaints and concerns & assist customers with online purchases
- Assisted with inventory control

IHOP Delray Beach, FL **Shift Supervisor** 09/2007 - 02/2011

- Ensured a smooth operation by upholding company standards & protocols
- Managed cash deposits, cash drawers, & financial shift reports
- Fulfilled the job position of a server, cook, and or hostess when needed to ensure operational success

Winn- Dixie BOYNTON BEACH, FL **Assistant Customer Service Manager** 03/2005 - 04/2007

- Trained new employees on company policies, procedures, techniques & customer service standards to ensure company objective is met.
- Ran & analyzed end of day financial reports to log them in the computer system
- Used listening & empathic skills to understand customer's complaints to resolve them in the most positive and efficient manner
- Assisted employees with customer service needs

Education

Palm Beach State College | Lake Worth, FL **Bachelor of Science** in Business Management & Supervision with a concentration in Entrepreneurship
12/2015